Vicki Hope

Email: vhope13@outlook.com | Phone: 770-540-5582 | Gainesville, GA 30506

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/visitVickiHope

GitHub: https://github.com/vwhope Website: https://vwhope.github.io/portfolio/

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer utilizing broad skillset to design and implement elegant online solutions to satisfy each customer's vision and requirements in a timely manner. Always striving to marry visually pleasing user interface design with back-end database functionality for a robust front-to-back solution. As a self-starter and team-player, will always bring accountability, problem-solving, strong communication skills and technical experience to every job.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript, Node.js, HTML, CSS, jQuery, Bootstrap, Ajax / API integration, Client-side data storage, Firebase, Git/Git Bash/GitHub

PROJECTS

Cryptofolio | https://cryptofolio-us.herokuapp.com/ Project organizer, front-end Home page, JavaScript and Sequelize ORM, MySQL database.

- group project, full-stack application that simulates a cryptocurrency portfolio manager
- integration of cryptocompare API, chart.js and passport-jwt

Plan-A-Date | https://asalmon.github.io/Plan-A-Date/ Project organizer, contributor to front-end design (HTML, CSS), also JavaScript Yelp API

- an application that reduces the complexity of planning an outing, by providing a centralized location to find food, entertainment and attractions (integrates APIs Yelp and SeatGeek)
- utilizes JavaScript, HTML, CSS, jQuery, Bootstrap, Material Design Lite, Superfish, Animate, Lightbox, Easing, WOW, Isotope, Touchswipe, Font-awesome and ionicons, responsive design

nexTrain | https://vwhope.github.io/nexTrain/ Sole code contributor/design

- a train timetable example that demonstrates ability to use Firebase and Moment.JS
- utilizes JavaScript, HTML, CSS, jQuery, Firebase, Moment.JS, custom Google font

TriviaGame | https://vwhope.github.io/TriviaGame/ Sole code contributor/layout, design

- a trivia game that demonstrates single page application, and use of timing events
- Utilizes JavaScript, HTML, CSS, jQuery, custom Google fonts

crystals-collector | https://wwhope.github.io/crystals-collector/ Sole code contributor/layout, design

- a crystal-collector game that demonstrates use of random number generator
- utilizes JavaScript, HTML, CSS, jQuery

word-guess-game | https://vwhope.github.io/word-guess-game/ Sole code contributor/layout, design

EXPERIENCE

<u>Bariatric Dietitian</u> – Northeast Georgia Health System – Gainesville, GA ______ 2014 – 2018

- Worked directly with hospital IT department to create custom template for out-patient dietitians.
- Extensive experience documenting in both Paragon and EPIC medical records.
- Software experience: Paragon Clinical Care Station, Paragon Patient Management, SCI Order Facilitator, SCI Maximizer, SimplifyMD, MS Office Suite, AllScripts, EPIC Cadence and EpicCare

Registry Clinical Dietitian – Emory – Johns Creek Hospital – Johns Creek, GA

2013 – 2014

- Created and maintained nutrition-related electronic medical record using ADIME format
- Gained knowledge and experience with Computrition software

Registry Clinical Dietitian – The Long Street Clinic (Obesity Solutions) – Gainesville, GA

2013 -2014

• Fulfilled office goals of preventing down-time and gaps in service by working with existing dietitian to manage schedule and balance patient load.

<u>Clinical Dietitian, Nutritionist</u> – Hope Nutrition Counseling, LLC – Gainesville, GA

2012 - 2013

- Achieved personal goal of creating nutrition-related business
- Embraced entrepreneurial spirit, learning invaluable small business skills
- Incorporated IT and nutrition skills designing, creating, implementing company website

Registry Clinical Dietitian – Emory – Wesley Woods LTAC – Atlanta, GA

2012 - 2013

• Exemplified software competency with CBORD nutrition software

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

<u>Co-owner/Layout and Design artist</u> – Blueprint Publishing, Inc. – Loganville, GA

<u>Co-owner/Developer</u> – DRV Technologies, Inc. – Alpharetta, GA

<u>Senior programmer/Project lead</u> – ACOM Solutions/Formula One Systems – Duluth, GA

<u>Junior programmer/Technical Support/Trainer</u> – ACOM Solutions/Formula One Systems – Duluth, GA

<u>Information Technology Coordinator</u> – The Times/Gannett Inc. – Gainesville, GA

<u>Regional Senior Operator</u> – *USA Today/Gannett Inc.* – Gainesville, GA

EDUCATION

Georgia Institute of Technology, Atlanta, GA – Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp

Emory Hospitals Dietetic Internship, Atlanta, GA – Dietetic Internship Certificate

The University of Georgia, Athens, GA – Bachelor of Science in Dietetics, Cum Laude

Brenau College, Gainesville, GA – Bachelor of Arts in Commercial Art, Minor in Spanish, Cum Laude